### Contact

julie.brown2@hcahealthcare.

www.linkedin.com/in/julie-brown-msn-rn-cphq-668072b0 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Process Improvement
Quality Measures
Operations Management

### Certifications

Certified Professionals in Healthcare Quality

# Julie Brown, MSN, RN, CPHQ

**Division Director of Clinical Informatics** 

Richmond, Virginia

## Summary

Experienced Director Of Clinical Informatics with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Operations Management, Physician Relations, Team Building, Software Documentation, and Healthcare. Strong operations professional with an MSN focused in Leadership and Management from Western Governors University.

## Experience

HCA Capital Division
Division Director of Clinical Informatics
June 2017 - Present (3 years 2 months)

Henrico Doctors' Hospital, HCA Director, Quality Data Processing February 2012 - June 2017 (5 years 5 months) Richmond, Virginia Area

- -Responsible for internal and external quality data for a multi-campus hospital group
- -Supervised Quality Data Specialists at three campuses
- -Worked collaboratively with the hospital and division leadership in developing a quality management strategy and annual goals
- -Coordinated and directed activities related to the collection, analysis and reporting of quality data
- -Lead the Quality Management Department in the development and application of quality management and cost reduction strategies throughout the hospital
- -Assumed responsibility for communication and education regarding quality management and data reporting activities in the organization and serves as a resource
- -Responsible for and provided direction for Core Measures, other quality data, patient safety and performance improvement

Walter Reed National Military Medical Center Clinical Data Quality Manager October 2006 - February 2012 (5 years 5 months) Bethesda, MD

- -Developed hospital's ORYX program
- -Position was 40% travel to Bethesda and 60% telework from Richmond
- -Co-chair of Outcomes Committee
- -Member of the integration team to maintain quality compliance with the integration of Walter Reed Army Medical Center and National Naval Medical Center
- -Collected concurrent data through electronic medical record reviews and reported outliers and near misses to champions on a daily basis
- -Identified opportunities, recommended improvements and facilitated communication between staff and departments
- -Coordinated multidisciplinary working groups
- -Served as liaison between external quality assessment programs and WRNMMC
- -Verified coding accuracy, coordinated corrections and communicated coding changes with external abstractor
- -Conducted concurrent and retrospective reviews of medical records for Patient Safety Indicators and Periodic Performance Review
- -Analyzed pertinent clinical performance data from the Population Health Navigator program
- -Performed trending, statistical control and other analyses on data
- -Maintained data currency on the WRNMMC Quality Dashboard

West Virginial Medical Institute
Quality Improvement Consultant
February 2001 - October 2006 (5 years 9 months)
Military Treatment Facilities

- -Performed data abstraction in eight military Medical Treatment Facilities in the mid-east region for the Joint Commission ORYX measures for the Department of Defense National Quality Management Program contract
- -Reviewed medical records and collected information about the quality of care for inpatient Core Measures and outpatient disease management for asthma, diabetes and hypertension
- -Analyzed data and developed reports for hospital administrators and clinicians
- -Identified areas of opportunity and recommended changes to improve compliance

- -Followed specifications set forth by the Joint Commission and National Hospital Quality Measures (NHQM)
- -Involved extensive developmental work in computers and a nationwide electronic network for the file transfers and communications, and sophisticated analytic work to turn data into useful information

Forensic Medical Advisory Service
Quality Improvement Abstractor
May 1999 - September 2000 (1 year 5 months)
Columbia, MD

Reviewed medical records from hospitals across the country for the pneumonia and stroke modules for HCFA's Sixth Scope of Work for Quality Improvement Organizations. FMAS implements the Health Care Quality Improvement Program to improve processes of care for Medicare Beneficiaries.

North Arundel Hospital RN January 1997 - April 1998 (1 year 4 months) Glen Burnie, MD

Staff Nurse on the Intermediate Care Unit

McLeod Regional Medical Center RN July 1993 - November 1996 (3 years 5 months) Florence, SC

Staff and charge nurse on the Cardiovascular Progressive Care Unit

### Education

Western Governors University

Master of Science - MS, Nursing Leadership and Management · (2016 - 2017)

Cedarville University

BSN, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1989 - 1993)